[{"question":" To add features, components, and permissions to your Android app, which file needs to be edited?","options":[{"text":"AndroidManifest.xml","correct":true},{"text":"Components.xml","correct":false},{"text":"AppManifest.xml","correct":false},{"text":"ComponentManifest.xml","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Which XML attribute should be used to make an Image View accessible?","options":[{"text":"android:talkBack","correct":false},{"text":"android:labelFor","correct":false},{"text":"android:hint","correct":false},{"text":"android:contentDescription","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" You launch your app, and when you navigate to a new screen it crashes, Which action will NOT help you diagnose the issue?","options":[{"text":"Set breakpoints and then step through the code line by line","correct":false},{"text":"Use the profiler tools in Android Studio to detect anomalies CPU, and network usage.","correct":false},{"text":"Add a Thread.sleep()call before you start the new activity.","correct":true},{"text":"inspect the logs in Logcat.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Why might push notifications stop working?","options":[{"text":"all of these answers","correct":true},{"text":"The device token is not being sent to push provider correctly.","correct":false},{"text":"Google Play Services is not installed on the deivce/emulator.","correct":false},{"text":"Battery optimization is turned on on the device.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" What is correct set of classes needed to implement a RecyclerView of items that displays a list of widgets vertically?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true}],"illustrator":"```\n      RecycleView\n      RecyclerView.Adapter<VH extends ViewHolder>\n      RecyclerView.ViewHolder\n      LinearLayoutManager\n```"},{"question":" The Android system kills process when it needs to free up memory. The likelihood of the system killing a given process depends on the state of the process and the activity at the time. With combination of process and activity state is most likely to be killed?","options":[{"text":"Process:In the background;Activity:Is stopped","correct":true},{"text":"Process:In the background;Activity:Is paused","correct":false},{"text":"Process:In the foreground;Activity:Is started","correct":false},{"text":"Process:In the foreground;Activity:Is paused","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" You have created a NextActivity class that relies on a string containing some data that pass inside the intent Which code snippet allows you to launch your activity?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\n        Intent(this, NextActivity::class.java).apply {\n            put(EXTRA_NEXT, \"some data\")\n        }.also { intent ->\n            activityStart(intent)\n        }\n```"},{"question":" You want to include about and setting modules in your project. Which files accurately reflects their inclusion?","options":[{"text":"in build.gradle:include ':app',':about' ':settings'","correct":false},{"text":"in settings.gradle:include ':app',':about' ':settings'","correct":true},{"text":"in settings.gradle:include ':about',':settings'","correct":false},{"text":"in gradle.properties:include ':app',':about' ':settings'","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" What is the benifit of using @VisibleForTesting annotation?","options":[{"text":"to denote that a class, methos, or field has its visibility relaxed to make code testable","correct":true},{"text":"to denote that a class, method, or field is visible only in the test code","correct":false},{"text":"to denote that a class, method, or field has its visibility increased to make code less testable","correct":false},{"text":"to throw a run-time error if a class, methos, or field with this annotation is accessed improperly","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". How would you specify in your build.gradle file that your app required at least API level 21 to run, but that it can be tested on API level 28?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true}],"illustrator":"```\n      defaultConfig {\n        ...\n      minSdkVersion 21\n        targetSdkVersion 28\n      }\n```"},{"question":". When will an activity's onActivityResult()be called?","options":[{"text":"when calling finish()in the parent activity","correct":false},{"text":"when placing an app into the background by sitching to another app","correct":false},{"text":"When onStop() is called in the target activity","correct":false},{"text":"when calling finish() in the target activity","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to remove an Event based on it;s id from your API, Which code snippet defines that request in Retrofit?","options":[{"text":"@DELETE(\"events)","correct":false},{"text":"@DELETE(\"events/{id}\")","correct":true},{"text":"@REMOVE(\"events/{id}\")","correct":false},{"text":"@DELETE(\"events/{id}\")","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". When would you use a product flavour in your build setup?","options":[{"text":"when you need to have the app's strings present in multiple lanuages","correct":false},{"text":"when you have to provide different versions of your app based on the physical device size","correct":false},{"text":"when you want to provide different versions of your app based on the device screen density","correct":false},{"text":"when you want to provide different version of your app with custom configuration and resources","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Given the fragment below, how would you get access to a TextView with an ID of text_home contained in the layout file of a Fragment class?","options":[{"text":"root.getById(R.id.text_home)","correct":false},{"text":"findViewByID(R.id.text_home)","correct":false},{"text":"root.findViewById(R.id.text_home)","correct":true},{"text":"root.find(R.id.text_home)","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\n    private lateinit var textView: TextView\n    override fun onCreateView(...): View? {\n        val root = inflator.inflator(R>layout.fragment_home, container, false)\n        textView = ??\n        return root\n    }\n```"},{"question":". Why do you use the AndroidJUnitRunner when running UI tests?","options":[{"text":"The test runner facilitates loading your test package and the app under test onto a device or emulator, runs the test, and reports the results.","correct":true},{"text":"The test runner creating screenshots of each screen that displayed while tests are executed.","correct":false},{"text":"The test runner facilitates parallelization of test classes by providing for each test class.","correct":false},{"text":"The test runner facilitates interacting with visible elements on a device, regardless of the activity or fragment that has focus.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What allows you to properly restore a user's state when an activity is restarted?","options":[{"text":"the onSaveInstance()method","correct":true},{"text":"all of these answers","correct":false},{"text":"persistent storage","correct":false},{"text":"ViewModel objects","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Given the definition below. how would you get access a TextView with an ID of text_home contained in thr layout file of a Fragment class?","options":[{"text":"root.find(R.id.text_home)","correct":false},{"text":"findViewById(R.id.text_home)","correct":false},{"text":"root.getById(R.id.text_home)","correct":false},{"text":"root.findViewById(R.id.text_home)","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". IF the main thread is blocked for too long, the system displays the\\_\\_\\_dialog?","options":[{"text":"Thread Not Responding","correct":false},{"text":"Application Paused","correct":false},{"text":"Application Not Responding","correct":true},{"text":"Application Blocked","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". How would you retrieve the value of a user's email from SharedPreferences while ensuring that the returned value is not null?","options":[{"text":"getPreferances(this).getString(Email,\"\")","correct":false},{"text":"getDefaultSharedPrefarances(this).getString(EMAIL,null)","correct":false},{"text":"getDefaultSharedPreferances(this).getString(EMAIL,\"\")","correct":true},{"text":"getPreferances(this).getString(EMAIL,null)","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Why is it problematic to define sizes using pixels on Android?","options":[{"text":"Although screen pixel density varies, this does not impact the use of pixels to define sizes.","correct":false},{"text":"Large devices always have more pixels, so your UI elements will be e=affected if you define them with pixels.","correct":false},{"text":"The same number of pixels may correspond to different physical sizes, affecting the appearance of your UI elements.","correct":false},{"text":"Different devices have different understanding of what a pixel is , affecting the appearance of your UI elements","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to get a list of devices that are attached to your computer with USB debugging enable. Which command would execute using the Android Debug Bridge?","options":[{"text":"list devices","correct":false},{"text":"adb devices","correct":true},{"text":"list avd","correct":false},{"text":"dir devices","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which drawable definition allows you to achieve the shape below?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\n    xml\n    <shape xmlns:android=\"http://schemas.android.com/apk/res/android\"\n        android:shape=\"oval\">\n        <stroke\n            android:width=\"4dp\"\n            android:color=\"@android:color/white\" />\n        <solid android:color=\"@android:color/white\" />\n    </shape>\n```"},{"question":". To persist a small collection of key-value data, what should you use?","options":[{"text":"external file storage","correct":false},{"text":"SharedPereferences","correct":true},{"text":"SQLite","correct":false},{"text":"internal file storage","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to retrieve a list of photos from an API. Which code snippet defines an HTML GET request in Retrofit?","options":[{"text":"@GET(\"photo/{id}\"}","correct":false},{"text":"@LIST(\"photo\")","correct":false},{"text":"@GET(\"photo\")","correct":false},{"text":"@GET(\"photo\")","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Given the test class below, which code snippet would be a correct assertion?","options":[{"text":"assertThat(resultAdd).is(2.0)","correct":false},{"text":"assertNotNull(resultAdd)","correct":true},{"text":"assertThat(resultAdd).isWqualTo(2.0)","correct":false},{"text":"assertThat(resultAdd)","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What tag should you use to add a reusable view component to a layout file?","options":[{"text":"`<merge/>`","correct":false},{"text":"`<include/>`","correct":true},{"text":"`<layout/>`","correct":false},{"text":"`<add/>`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You want to provide a different drawable for devices that are in landscape mode and whose language is set to French. which directory is named correctly?","options":[{"text":"fr-land-drawable","correct":false},{"text":"drawable-fr-land","correct":true},{"text":"drawable-french-land","correct":false},{"text":"french-land-drawable","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Why might you need to include the following permission to your app?","options":[{"text":"to monitor the location of the devices so that you don't attempt to make network calls when the user is stationary","correct":false},{"text":"to request the ability to make network calls from your app","correct":true},{"text":"to monitor the network state of the device so that you can display an in-app banner to the user","correct":false},{"text":"to monitor the network state of the devices so that you don't attempt to make network calls when the network is unavailable","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which image best corresponds to the following `LinearLayout`?","options":[{"text":"A","correct":false},{"text":"B","correct":true},{"text":"C","correct":false},{"text":"D","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\n    xml\n    <LinearLayout\n        android:layout_width=\"match_parent\"\n\tandroid:layout_height=\"match_parent\"\n\tandroid:orientation=\"horizontal\"\n\tandroid:gravity=\"center\">\n\t<Button\n            android:layout_width=\"wrap_content\"\n            android:layout_height=\"wrap_content\"\n            android:text=\"Button\" />\n\t<Button\n            android:layout_width=\"wrap_content\"\n            android:layout_height=\"wrap_content\"\n            android:text=\"Button\" />\n        </LinearLayout>\n```"},{"question":". You want to open the default Dialer app on a device. What is wrong with this code?","options":[{"text":"`startActivityWithResult()` should be used instead of `startActivity()` when using `Intent.ACTION_DIAL`.","correct":true},{"text":"For `Intent.ACTION_DIAL`, the `Intent` option `Intent.FLAG_ACTIVITY_NEW_TASK` must be added when using this `dialerIntent`.","correct":false},{"text":"The `dialerIntent` will cause an ActivityNotFoundException to be thrown on devices that do not support `Intent.ACTION_DIAL`.","correct":false},{"text":"The permission `android.permission.CALL_PHONE` must be requested first before `Intent.ACTION_DIAL` can be used.","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nval dialerIntent = Intent()\nval et = findViewById(R.id.some_edit_text)\ndialerIntent.action = Intent.ACTION_DIAL\ndialerIntent.data = Uri.parse(\"tel:\" + et.getText()?.toString())\nstartActivity(dialerIntent)\n```"},{"question":". When should you store files in the `/assets` directory?","options":[{"text":"when you need access to the original file names and file hierarchy","correct":true},{"text":"when you need access to the file with its `resource ID`, like `R.assets.filename`","correct":false},{"text":"when you have XML files that define tween animations","correct":false},{"text":"when you need to access the file in its raw form using `Resources.openRawResource()`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You want to allow users to take pictures in your app. Which is _not_ an advantage of creating an appropriate `intent`, instead of requesting the camera permission directly?","options":[{"text":"Users can select their favorite photo apps to take pictures.","correct":false},{"text":"You do not have to make a permission request in your app to take a picture.","correct":false},{"text":"You have full control over the user experience. The app that handles the camera `intent` will respect your design choices.","correct":true},{"text":"You do not have to design the UI. The app that handles the camera `intent` will provide the UI.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". When would you use the `ActivityCompat.shouldShowRequestPermissionRationale()` function?","options":[{"text":"when a user first opens your app and you want to provide an explanation for the use of a given permission","correct":false},{"text":"when a user has previously denied the request for a given permission and selects \"Tell me more\"","correct":false},{"text":"when a user has previously denied the request for a given permission and you want to provide an explanation for its use","correct":false},{"text":"when a user has previously denied the request for a given permission and selected \"Don't ask again,\" but you need the permission for your app to function","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You would like to enable analytics tracking only in `release` builds. How can you create a new field in the generated `BuildConfig` class to store that value?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nbuildTypes {\n\tdebug {\n\t\tbuildConfigField 'boolean', 'ENABLE_ANALYTICS', 'true'\n\t}\n\trelease {\n\t\tbuildConfigField 'boolean', 'ENABLE_ANALYTICS', 'false'\n\t}\n}\n```"},{"question":". To optimize your APK size, what image codec should you use?","options":[{"text":"JPG","correct":false},{"text":"PNG","correct":false},{"text":"MPEG","correct":false},{"text":"WebP","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You have built code to make a network call and tested that it works in your development environment. However, when you publish it to the Play console, the networking call fails to work. What will _not_ help you troubleshoot this issue?","options":[{"text":"checking whether `ProGuard` -keepclassmembers have been added to the network data transfer objects (DTOs) in question","correct":false},{"text":"using the profiler tools in Android Studio to detect anomalies in CPU, memory, and network usage","correct":true},{"text":"checking for exceptions in the server logs or server console","correct":false},{"text":"checking that the network data transfer object has `@SerizlizedName` applied to its member properties","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which code snippet would achieve the layout displayed below?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nxml\n    <androidx.constraintlayout.widget.ConstraintLayout\n\t...>\n\t<TextView\n\t\tandroid:id=\"@+id/text_dashboard\"\n\t\tandroid:layout_width=\"match_parent\"\n\t\tandroid:layout_height=\"wrap_content\"\n\t\tandroid:layout_marginStart=\"8dp\"\n\t\tandroid:layout_marginTop=\"16dp\"\n\t\tandroid:layout_marginEnd=\"8dp\"\n\t\tandroid:padding=\"8dp\"\n\t\tandroid:text=\"Dashboard\"\n\t\tapp:layout_constraintEnd_toEndOf=\"parent\"\n\t\tapp:layout_constraintStart_toStartOf=\"parent\"\n\t/>\n</androidx.constraintlayout.widget.ConstraintLayout>\n```"},{"question":". Which source set is `_not_` available to you by default when Android Studio creates a new project?","options":[{"text":"test","correct":false},{"text":"androidTest","correct":false},{"text":"app","correct":false},{"text":"main","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which definition will prevent other apps from accessing your `Activity` class via an `intent`?","options":[{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nxml\n\t<activity android:name=\".ExampleActivity\">\n\t\t<intent-filter>\n\t\t\t<action android:name=\"android.intent.action.VIEW\" />\n\t\t</intent-filter>\n\t</activity>\n```"},{"question":". To preserve on-device memory, how might you determine that the user's device has limited storage capabilities?","options":[{"text":"Use the `ActivityManager.isLowRamDevice()` method to find out whether a device defines itself as \"low RAM.\"","correct":true},{"text":"Use the `Activity.islowRam()` method to find out whether a device defines itself as \"low RAM.\"","correct":false},{"text":"Use the `ConnectivityManager.hasLowMemory()` method to find out whether a device defines itself as \"low RAM.\"","correct":false},{"text":"Make an image download request and check the remaining device storage usage.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is `_not_` a good way to reuse Android code?","options":[{"text":"Use a common Gradle module shared by different Android projects.","correct":false},{"text":"Prefer to build custom views or fragments over activities.","correct":false},{"text":"Prefer to build activities instead of fragments.","correct":false},{"text":"Break down UI layouts into common elements and use `<include/>` to include them in other layout XML files.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which layout is best for large, complex hierarchies?","options":[{"text":"LinearLayout","correct":false},{"text":"ConstraintLayout","correct":true},{"text":"FrameLayout","correct":false},{"text":"RelativeLayout","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to upgrade to the latest version of the Android Gradle plugin. Which file should you modify?","options":[{"text":"root_project_dir/app/build.gradle.","correct":true},{"text":"root_project_dir/settings.gradle.","correct":false},{"text":"root_project_dir/build.gradle.","correct":false},{"text":"root_project_dir/app/gradle.properties.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Why do developers often put app initialization code in the Application class?","options":[{"text":"The Application class is instantiated before any other class when the process for the application is created.","correct":false},{"text":"The Application class is instantiated after any permissions requests when the process for the application is created.","correct":false},{"text":"The Application class is created each time a new Activity is launched, making it ideal for initialization code.","correct":false},{"text":"The Application class is created each time a background service is called, making it ideal for initialization code.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What folder should you use for your app's launcher icons?","options":[{"text":"/drawable","correct":false},{"text":"/icon","correct":false},{"text":"/mipmap","correct":true},{"text":"/launcher","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which drawable definition allows you to achieve the shape below?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nxml\n\t<shape xmlns:android-\"http://schemas.android.com/apk/res/android\"\n\t   android:shape-\"rectangle\">\n\t   <gradient\n\t      android:startColor-\"@android:color/white\"\n\t      android:endColor-\"@android:color/black\"\n\t      android:angle-\"98\"/>\n\t</shape>\n```"},{"question":". Given the ConstraintLayout below, which statement is true?","options":[{"text":"View B is not horizontally constrained.","correct":false},{"text":"View C has too many constraints.","correct":false},{"text":"View B is not vertically constrained.","correct":false},{"text":"View C is constrained to the parent.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Given this code snippey from a build.gradle file, which choice is not a possible build variant?","options":[{"text":"productionDebug.","correct":false},{"text":"developmentDebug.","correct":false},{"text":"stagingDebug.","correct":false},{"text":"stagingRelease.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is not good way to reuse Android code?","options":[{"text":"Break down UI layouts into common elements and use <include/> to include them in other layout XML files.","correct":false},{"text":"Prefer to build custom views or fragments over activities.","correct":false},{"text":"Use a common Gradle module shared by different Android projects.","correct":false},{"text":"Prefer to build activities instead of fragments.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". When should you use the androidTest directory to store your test classes?","options":[{"text":"when the tests consist only of unit tests.","correct":false},{"text":"when the number of tests to run is large(500+).","correct":false},{"text":"when the tests need to run on your local machine.","correct":false},{"text":"when the tests need to run on real or virtual devices.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the benifit of using the @VisibleForTesting annotation?","options":[{"text":"to denote that a class, method, or field is visible only in test code.","correct":false},{"text":"to denote that a class, method or field has it's visibility increased to make code less testable.","correct":false},{"text":"to denote that a class, method, or field has it's visibility relaxed to make code testable.","correct":true},{"text":"to throw a run-time error if a class, method, or field which this annotation is accessed improperly.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Given an APK named app-internal-debug.apk produced from the build process, which statement is likely to be true?","options":[{"text":"This APK is created on a developer machine from the debug product flavor.","correct":false},{"text":"This APK is created from the internalDebug product flavor.","correct":false},{"text":"This APK created from the debug product flavor and internal build type.","correct":false},{"text":"This APK is created from the debug build type and internal product flavor.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". When attempting to build your project, what might the following error indicate?","options":[{"text":"You have included incorect format information in your build.gradle file.","correct":false},{"text":"You have added more than 20 dependencies to your build.gradle.","correct":false},{"text":"You have exceeded the total number of methods that can be referenced within a single DEX file.","correct":true},{"text":"You have a NullPointerException in your code.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which statement, in build.gradle file, correctly denotes that the corresponding module is an Android library module?","options":[{"text":"apply plugin: 'com.module.library'","correct":false},{"text":"apply plugin: 'com.android.library'","correct":true},{"text":"apply plugin: 'com.module.library'","correct":false},{"text":"include plugin: 'com.module.library'","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Given the following dimens.xml file, how would you define an ImageView with medium spacing at the bottom?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true}],"illustrator":"```\n<ImageView\n   android:id=@+id/image_map_pin\"\n   android:layout_width=\"wrap_content\"\n   android:layout_heignt=\"wrap_content\"\n   android:layout_marginBottom=\"@dimen/spacing_medium\"\n   android:src=@drawable/map_pin />\n```"},{"question":". what is not a benefit of externalizing app resources such as image and string from a code?","options":[{"text":"It allows Android to choose the appropriate resource based on the current configuration during runtime.","correct":true},{"text":"It allows you to have more performant applications because the code and resources are separated.","correct":false},{"text":"It allows you to provide a different Ul experience based on the user's language settings.","correct":false},{"text":"It allows you to provide a different Ul experience based on the user's device size.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the chief purpose of line five in this code snippet?","options":[{"text":"to make sure that the activity finishes when the savedInstanceState is not null","correct":false},{"text":"to make sure that the activity creates a new fragment each time it is restored from a previous state","correct":true},{"text":"to prevent the display of two fragments side by side in cases where the activity is restored from a previous state","correct":false},{"text":"to prevent the creation of overlapping fragments in cases where the activity is restored from a previous state","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\noverride fun onCreate(savedInstanceState: Bundle?) { super.onCreate(savedInstanceState) setContentView(R.layout.activity_post_create)\n\tif (savedInstanceState != null) return\n\tval fragment = CreatePostFragment()\n\t\tsupportFragmentManager\n\t\t.beginTransaction()\n\t\t.add(R.id. fragment_container, fragment)\n\t\t.commit()\n}\n```"}]